All right, it's 10.30,
so we can get started.
It seems like the buses are on
you late or something,
but welcome, everyone.
As you know, Homework 3 is due
tomorrow, and Homework 4 will be
released tomorrow.
A couple of new announcements.
I added some Zoom office hours
by appointment,
because frankly, no one really
was coming to Zoom office hours
and then I was kind of just
sitting there waiting and also
just to like you know optimize
my time I tried to do Zoom
office hours for both of my
classes at the same time but
they have different Zoom links
and you can't have two Zooms on
one computer at a time so I had
to have my laptop and my iPad
open couldn't really do anything
else and no one was there so I
was like you know what better
idea would be to just do this by
appointment so now if you click
this link here I have like
several 15 minute slots
throughout the week and I'll
update these every few weeks So
like I'd say your best bet is to
rely on in-person office hours,
which still exist and are not
going anywhere I will still have
office hours after lecture but
if there's something you want to
talk about whether it's content
related or otherwise and you
can't make it to one of those or
One of the other regularly
scheduled zoom office hours like
to rule has them on Thursdays
Then you can click this link and
we can shop
Okay
Lastly our midterm is coming up
shockingly quickly.
It's in a week from this Tuesday
And so one thing to help you
prepare that students in the
past have really liked is we are
going to do a Practice exam next
Friday.
Okay.
So the way it's gonna work is
it's already scheduled It's on
the calendar.
If you scroll to week five,
you'll see it.
It's from 2 30 to 5 30 next
Friday
In 1013 Dow, which is right
across the hall here And it's
actually the room that our
actual exam is going to be in as
well
Which I'll you know make a post
about on ed sometime next week
But the idea with the practice
midterm is for the first two
hours what we're gonna do is
we're just gonna print out last
spring's midterm one and so you
shouldn't look at it until then
and The idea is that you're just
gonna simulate what it's like to
actually take the exam So you
can like bring in your one
double-sided note sheet Which
I'm not sure if I've announced
yet, but it may be in the
syllabus You can bring in your
one double-sided note sheet, but
it's gonna like we're gonna
pretend like you're actually
taking the exam So like can't
have your Spotify open can't
check stuff in the course notes
We're going to pretend like this
is the real exam,
do that for two hours, and then
we'll take it up for the final
hour.
Students in the past have said
that this is an effective review
session strategy, so we're going
to do that.
So come on Friday,
and if you can't make it, of
course,
the midterm that we're going to
do, spring 26 midterm one, is
already posted along with its
solutions, and we're going to
record that last hour as well,
and we'll post that for those of
you who can't make it.
But it's totally fine if you
have another lab from 2.30
to 4.30,
you can just show up at 4.30
as well.
You can come and leave whenever
you want.
OK,
so that's what's coming up
logistics-wise.
And again, more details about
all of this will come sometime
in the next week on Ed.
The plan for today is to start
by recapping the big idea from
Tuesday's class, which is that
of orthogonal projections.
And then I talked to the TAs
after lab, and there was one
question that we thought
would be useful for me to review
here.
So we will do a little bit of
that.
Then the next big idea is that
of thinking about if we have a
collection of vectors.
We have D vectors.
And you think about the set of
all vectors you can make using
linear combinations of those D
vectors.
What is that set?
Is it a line? Is it a plane? Is
it something else?
That is the next big idea.
And essentially that,
that is the collection of linear
combinations of a set of
vectors,
is the main idea discussed in
chapter four, which is the final
chapter of the notes that is in
scope for midterm one.
So we're going to start with 4.1
and 4.2
today.
But first, let's recap the idea
of an orthogonal projection.
Can someone remind me if I have
a vector u here
and a vector v here, what is the
orthogonal projection of u onto
v?
What does that mean?
What was the orthogonal
projection of u onto v?
What was that?
Alex.
It's making a vector in the same
direction as v that most closely
matches u.
That was the intuitive way I
wanted you to think about this.
The orthogonal projection of u
onto v
is the vector in the direction
of v
that is as close to u as
possible.
How was that measured?
The way we measured how close
our approximation was was by
subtracting u from the scalar
multiple of v we found.
So these are all scalar
multiples of v.
We're looking for the scalar
multiple of v that is closest to
u.
And that vector we gave the name
p,
which is the orthogonal
projection of u onto v.
And we also called it k star
times v.
What was K-star?
It's a scalar.
It told us how much of v we
should take to make this
orthogonal projection.
What was that amount? Do you
remember?
U dot v over v dot z.
Good.
But you notice this is also the
same as u dot v over the length
of v squared.
And what was the defining
characteristic of this
orthogonal projection vector p?
How did we find k star?
How did we know that this was
the right amount of v to take
and not some other amount?
What was the thinking there?
You drew a vector u minus kv,
and you know that that has to be
orthogonal to kv and so you know
their dot products can be zero
and then you can do algebra on
that.
Good indeed the main idea is
that here p
is the orthogonal projection
of u onto v and the reason it is
the orthogonal projection
is because the error that is the
difference between u and that
orthogonal projection vector p
is orthogonal to p itself.
That right angle is between e
and p, which is also
between e and v,
because p and v live on the same
line.
Now,
one of the ideas I want to
review
is sort of a consequence of this
setup, which is that here we've
decomposed u into the sum of two
pieces.
I didn't explicitly write it
like this last class,
but here we've written u as the
sum of one thing plus another
thing.
This picture shows us how to
break up u into two pieces.
What are those two pieces we've
broken up u into?
What's that one? It's our v and
e.
Good.
Or, yeah, it's the same thing as
P and E.
And what is the significance of
writing it that way?
This is true, sure, but what is
convenient about this?
Or what is maybe interesting
about this?
Emma.
E is parallel to V and E is
orthogonal to E? Exactly.
The big idea here is that I've
written u as the sum of two
building blocks that are
orthogonal to each other p and e
Notice there's a right angle
here.
So this is sort of like a
rotated version of the x and
y-axes
Okay
And this we might call an
orthogonal decomposition
of U.
Now what does this have to do
with any of the lab questions?
Well,
remember there was this question
in Activity 5, where we give you
three vectors v1, v2, and v3,
and then a fourth vector u, and
we say hey write u as a linear
combination of v1, v2, and v3.
Now at first this seems like a
totally unrelated idea because
in this recap here I said
nothing about linear
combinations.
Okay, I just said approximate
one vector using another And
then we saw this nice picture
But it turns out that you can
solve this linear combinations
problem using the fact that as
the question tells us
V1 V2 and V3 are pairwise
orthogonal Which means V1 dot V2
is 0 V1 dot V3 is 0 and V2 dot
V3 is 0 I don't have a visual
for this, but we're looking at
three vectors in R3
We're thinking of like, I don't
know, my legs plus my arms here.
That's like the picture you
should have in your mind.
Or like, you know, right hand
rule from physics,
like v1, v2, v3, they're living
somewhere out in R3,
but this is their general
orientation.
All orthogonal to each other.
So what this question is asking
us to do is fill in the blanks.
something times v1 plus
something times v2 plus
something times v3 is equal to
you okay and one of the things
you practiced is figuring out
what those somethings are
supposed to be without knowing
anything about projections and
orthogonality like I know you
know how to set up a system of
three equations three unknowns
and you could do it okay but
we're trying to think of more
clever ways of figuring out what
to multiply you v1 v2 and v3 by
without having to solve that
system, because again, that's
annoying.
No one really wants to do that.
What's the key insight here?
What's the key insight?
Remember, the main idea from the
last slide
is when I projected u onto v,
what that gave me was this
decomposition of u into the sum
of these building blocks that
are at right angles.
Here I also have building blocks
that are at right angles.
How do you think we may be able
to find the amounts to multiply
each building block by?
Without needing to solve a
system of equations.
Yeah, Alex.
It's related to that.
Let me just write
here,
Q.
How do we find these scalars
without needing
to solve a system of
equations?
Well,
one of the last ideas we
discussed was one that went
something like this.
Suppose it is possible to make u
using v1, v2, and v3.
That isn't guaranteed.
If I gave you three vectors in
R3,
but they were like 1, 0, 0, 2,
0, 0, and 3, 0, 0,
and the vector u was like 1, 1,
1, then you can't make u.
Because 1, 0, 0, 2, 0, 0, and 3,
0, 0,
their linear combinations really
just are the same as the linear
combinations of 1, 0, 0.
So you couldn't make 1, 1, 1.
That's something we're going to
talk a little bit more about
later today.
I assume it's a given that you
can make u,
which is the case in this
question.
One of the last arguments I gave
you on Tuesday was sort of
starting with this linear
combination form for you
and using the fact that the v's
are orthogonal to tell us what
the a's should be.
Does anyone remember what that
argument was?
What did I do to this equation
to tell me what the a's are
supposed to be?
Remember, in this specific
question, I told you that the
v's are orthogonal to each
other.
That's the part I highlighted
back here.
Zara.
Did you take the dot, how did
you handle this? Yeah, what I
did is I said, hey, let's just
see what happens if I take the
dot product of this equation
with v1 on both sides.
And there's nothing special
about v1.
That's what I did last time.
Let's just pick a different one.
Let's pick v2,
for example.
What do I get on the left? u dot
v2,
what do I get on the right? I
get this whole thing.
A1 v1 plus A2 v2 plus A3 v3, all
of that dotted
with v2.
But if I distribute this dot
product,
this looks like A1 times v1 dot
v2
plus A2 times v2 dot v2
plus a3 times v3 dot v2.
Notice I'm intentionally not
putting dots here, here, and
here because this is just scalar
times scalar.
And I'm trying to be deliberate
with only using that dot symbol
when I'm talking about the dot
product between two vectors.
Okay, what was the next thing
that brought us closer to having
a clean formula for one of the
a's?
Okay.
Since they're orthogonal,
would v1 dot v2 be 0 and then v3
dot v2 also be 0?
Exactly.
The v's are all orthogonal to
each other, so whenever I have a
vi dot a vj where i and j are
not the same,
I have a 0 here.
So what comes out of the dust?
First,
we have u dot v2 is equal to
a2 times v2 dot
v2.
But if I divide both sides by v2
dot v2,
what this tells me is that a2,
that is the number I'm supposed
to multiply v2 by in this linear
combination,
is u dot v2 over v2 dot v2.
And that number should be
familiar it's just the amount
that I would multiply v2 by if I
were projecting u onto just
v2.
So I've turned this bigger
problem of figuring out how to
make u using three building
blocks into three
smaller projection problems.
Turns out I can just project it
onto v1,
project it onto v2,
project it onto v3, and add up
those projections.
And the reason that that works
here is because these building
blocks v were orthogonal.
So this is just like the
three-dimensional extension
of what we did previously,
where I broke u into the sum of
two vectors that are at right
angles.
I'm doing that with three
vectors now, because I was given
a v1, v2, and v3 that were at
right angles.
So the main idea here is that
whenever you are given v's that
are orthogonal,
making another vector using a
linear combination of those v's
is typically easy.
OK, so we prefer using building
blocks that are orthogonal.
What questions do we have so
far?
What questions do we have?
Sam.
When we find that A,
do we still need to find more
variables, or are we done?
I just showed you how you would
find one of those three, which
is A2.
So the formula we just covered
would tell us what to put here.
For the other two,
I would just replace the V2s
with V1s, and that would give me
A1.
And replace the V2s with V3s,
and that would give me A3.
So I'd have to compute a
fraction like this three times.
Yeah,
clarifying question.
There's nothing special about V2
and A2.
I just wanted to use an example
that wasn't v1 and a1.
Yeah, Esther.
What if we have more than three
terms?
The vector size is five.
Sure.
Then we would just say,
you're saying if there's a plus
a4 v4 and a plus a5 v5?
Well, we're going to talk a
little bit about this in just a
bit.
But it's impossible to have five
vectors in 3D that are all
perpendicular to each other.
Because 3D,
if you think of the room around
us,
It only has like three
independent directions in which
you can move.
So you can try it right now with
your fingers.
You can't make four directions
that are all perpendicular to
each other.
The most you can do is three.
But if the vectors lived in R5
and you had five perpendicular
vectors,
yeah, the same logic would
apply.
The vectors could live in R74
and we could have 74
perpendicular vectors and the
same logic would apply.
Yeah, good.
OK,
one thing I want to clarify
before we move into the new
ideas in chapter 4 is that all
we have learned to do so far
is project one
vector onto one other vector.
And this idea that we can use
this to help us more efficiently
find scalars for linear
combinations was an application
of this idea here.
So far we've only learned how to
project one vector onto another.
But soon we're gonna want to
learn how to do more than that.
Soon,
this is the world in which I'm
going to live.
Pretend I have a vector u.
I don't know why the subscripts
on the v's are looking a little
weird.
I have a vector u.
And in blue,
what I've drawn is a plane.
And what we're going to define
in just a moment is that this is
the plane spanned by two
vectors,
v1 and v2.
Here's my question.
Can I make u as a linear
combination of these v's?
Can it be done?
This vector u,
can it be made as a linear
combination of these v's?
I'm seeing some no's.
Yeah, Zara?
I was going to say no because
when you like,
you don't want to know how to do
the same thing here with y,
it's going to lie on the plane
and it doesn't.
Exactly.
This plane represents all of the
linear combinations of v1 and
v2.
So anything that you can make
with v1 and v2 would be on the
plane.
But u, as you can see, is not on
the plane,
which means it cannot be made as
a linear combination of v1 and
v2.
So then the next question we
would ask is, well,
then among all of the linear
combinations of v1 and v2,
which one is closest to u?
Do we see how that's the next
natural question to ask, given
everything we've just discussed?
But that's a more complicated
thing to answer, because so far
we've only learned how to
project one vector onto one
other vector.
But this is asking for more than
that.
This is asking, how do we
project one vector
onto the set of linear
combinations of multiple other
vectors,
or project one vector onto a
plane?
That's more complicated.
But that's the picture we're
going to return to.
And at some point after midterm
1, before midterm 2, we're going
to redraw the same picture and
connect this to the multiple
linear regression problem.
Because this is,
I'll say this again in a month,
But understanding how to project
one vector
onto a plane like this is
probably the most important idea
we will cover this semester.
I want to plant that seed for
now.
We don't yet know enough to
answer that.
We need to introduce the idea of
a matrix to get there.
But that's where we're heading,
figuring out among all the
vectors on this plane, which one
is closest to you,
knowing that u is not on the
plane.
Eventually, we will get there.
OK?
But to answer that question,
we need to have a better
understanding of what it means
to consider the set of all
linear combinations of some
vectors.
The example of that that you're
familiar with now,
based on the visual I just
showed you,
was that the set of all linear
combinations of two vectors in
R3 is a plane.
And that was the plane we just
saw in blue.
Okay,
but what if what if we think
more abstractly like what is the
set of all linear combinations
of seven vectors in our five?
I don't know.
We need some terminology to
discuss this idea, which is what
we are going to now discuss.
Okay So now let's start with
chapter
4.1
And so here's what I'll say
suppose
We have an arbitrary number of
vectors v1 v2 all the way
through v Who remembers the
placeholder I said we would use
for the number of vectors we
have in an arbitrary situation?
D,
good.
And we'll say that these vectors
are all in Rn.
So I have d vectors, they all
have n things in them.
In the visuals I've shown you, n
was always 2 or 3.
But we will think about these
ideas in higher dimensional n's
today as well.
These v's are what I will
intuitively call our building
blocks.
The span,
this is the new term of the day,
of these vectors This
is the set
of all possible
linear combinations of them.
Now,
can someone remind me, what does
a general linear combination of
these d vectors look like?
If I wanted to write out a
template for what a linear
combination of these things is.
What would that template look
like?
Yeah, Gavin.
A V1 plus V V2 plus dot dot dot
plus some other
letter V V.
Good.
So to avoid the fact that we
don't know what the value of D
is, I'm just going to call the
scalars A's.
A general linear combination is
going to look something like A1
V1 plus A2 V2 plus dot dot
dot A,
D,
V, D.
Now, if we were dealing with one
specific question and we knew
that we only had V1, V2, V3,
maybe we would call this A, B,
and C.
But because this is a general
definition, we don't know how
many vectors there are,
this is what we'll use.
This is what one linear
combination of them looks like.
But what I want to describe is
the set of all possible such
vectors.
Like, I want to describe every
vector that can be made this
way.
Does anyone know how to stitch
this together, maybe using set
builder notation?
Just summation from A-I-B-I.
I see your idea,
but what you've proposed is a
way to just write this
expression a little more
concisely.
But that would still be the same
expression.
What I'm more getting at is,
like, I need a way to write down
on the page the set of all
possible vectors of this form.
Here's what I was getting at.
What I'm going to do is wrap
this with set notation
and say, give me all of the
terms of this form where the
a's all belong to the set of
real
numbers.
That is how you would describe
the set of all possible vectors
of the form a1 v1 plus a2 v2
that could exist.
So in this setting,
you have to imagine I'm giving
you d vectors.
Like I give you three vectors in
R5.
The set of all of their linear
combinations, which is their
span, is this set.
It's the set of all vectors that
you can make by taking some
amount of the first plus some
amount of the second plus some
amount of the third where those
amounts can be any real number.
You can imagine, I mean, this is
sort of a intuitive thing, not
something you could actually do
because the real numbers are
infinite.
But if you four looped over
every real number for A1 and A2
and A3, that would fill out the
span of these vectors.
But of course, you can't four
loop over the real numbers.
And so this set is what I would
call the span of
those vectors.
And the way I will denote that
is by the span function,
which takes as an input these
v's.
Note that I've used set notation
twice here.
The first is in the output, and
the second is in the input.
So span is really just a new
word
describing a concept we kind of
have already seen before.
The span of two vectors in R3 is
a plane.
Span is just a shortcut for
saying the set of all linear
combinations of.
But really, the two vectors in
R3 spanning a plane is just one
specific example.
What I want to give us is a more
general understanding of, OK, I
have d vectors in Rn.
What do they span?
And how I'm going to do this is
by first starting with one
vector,
thinking about all of the things
it could span in R2, R3, R100.
Then think about two vectors.
What are all the things it could
span in R2, R3, R100?
Then three vectors, what are all
the things that could span?
R2, R3,
and R100.
And then in general, d vectors,
what are all the things that
could span,
OK?
So why don't we start with one
vector,
which means d equals 1.
Let's start with R2.
So let's consider the vector, I
don't know,
v equals 1,
2.
What is the span of the vector
1,
2 in R2?
Yeah? Is it just like the scalar
times the vector?
So a scalar times v is just one
of the many vectors in the span.
The lines that the vector lies
on? Exactly.
So the span is the set of all
scalar multiples of v.
Good,
exactly.
So recall,
if this is v,
well then 2 times v is going to
look like this.
Same direction, double the
length.
Negative 3 times v is going to
look something like this.
Points in the opposite direction
triple the length.
Pi times v is going to be
somewhere over there.
Half of v is going to look
something like that.
All of those scalar multiples of
v live in this line.
And similarly, if I pick any
point on this line,
I could think of what scalar
multiple I would have to
multiply v by to get there.
Okay, and so this line
is
the span of v,
okay,
and if I want to write this in
set notation,
I would write it as the set of
all vectors of the form a times
1,
2, where a is a real number.
Doesn't matter what letter I use
here.
If you look in the notes,
sometimes instead of a, we'll
write t.
t is a common choice for a
scalar or placeholder in this
setting.
OK?
Now,
what is another equation for
this line?
What if I just want a regular y
equals mx plus b type equation
for this line?
How could I describe it?
Not that we need one.
This is a perfectly valid way of
describing a line,
saying it's a set of all vectors
whose endpoints live on the
line.
And that set comes from
multiplying 1, 2 by all possible
real numbers.
Yeah?
y equals 2x.
How did you think of that?
I just looked at v,
and then I did rise over run.
Good.
Yeah, that's all it is.
If you take a look at the vector
that spans the line, v,
it consists of all of the
vectors where the y component is
double the x component.
If you multiply v by any number,
17,
you'll get 17 and 34,
which means y is still 2 times
x.
So y equals 2x is the same line
that the set builder notation
I've just highlighted describes.
So we have a new way of
describing a line.
One thing I want to point out
here
is that the line passes through
0, 0.
Why is that?
Like, why do I know for sure it
passes through 0, 0?
I guess at 0,
would you want the scalar
constants?
Exactly.
What if I multiply v by 0?
That should give me the vector
0, 0.
And since this line is supposed
to contain every scalar multiple
of v,
it should also contain 0, 0.
Note that we only have one
building block vector, v, here.
So the set that I've
highlighted,
a times 1, 2, where a is a real
number,
is the set of all linear
combinations of v.
It's just a little strange to
think of it as a linear
combination because there's only
one vector.
You only have one building
block.
The only thing you can do is
change how much of it you're
taking.
There's nothing to add to.
I have a misunderstanding of
this concept,
but how does that work if the
vector,
like I thought you said early in
the semester, that the placement
of the vector doesn't matter.
Where it physically is on the
graph.
That is true.
But suppose we consider 1, 2,
and all of its scalar multiples,
which are like 2,
4,
3, 6,
0, 0.
There's only one line that
contains all of those vectors
and it's the one that goes
through the origin.
So, what I think will sort of
address your concern is how
would we describe a line that
doesn't go through the origin?
Okay,
because this one,
if you take for a moment that,
you know, take at face value
what I'm saying,
the span of a vector has to
contain 0, 0.
What about lines that don't pass
through 0, 0?
Like this one.
Let's just pick two points here.
0 comma 6 and 3 comma 12.
OK?
That line.
This doesn't contain the origin,
so it's not
The span of any one vector.
But I can still kind of describe
it
like the span of a vector.
It's just offset a little.
You see what I'm getting at?
Pretend this whole line, if I
dragged it down six units,
and it did pass through the
origin.
And then I could describe it as
the span of a vector.
What vector could I describe it
as the span of?
If it did go through the origin,
I pulled it down,
there is a vector, there is
plenty of vectors.
The answer is not unique,
that I could describe this line
as a span of.
Yeah?
3, 6.
How'd you think of that? When
you drag it down by 6, I just
subtract it 6 from 12.
Good.
Another way to think about it,
if you don't even want to drag
it down, is think about the
change in y and change in x.
What's the change in y here? 6.
What's the change in x? 3.
So it seems like this line has a
direction that moves 3 to the
right and 6 up.
So it's the same vector as the
other one, though, right?
Because they're both just 2,
like the slope is 3.
Yeah, you can also call it 1, 2.
OK, so it is the same vector,
it's just? The direction vector
is the same, but this is not the
same line.
So the question is, how do you
describe this line? And this is
a good segue, so I'm glad you
asked the question.
I could describe this line like
this.
It's the set of all scalar
multiples of 1,
2,
or 3, 6,
but there's something added to
all of those.
There's a plus something.
0,
6, sure.
But that's not the only thing I
could put there.
I could put any point on the
line
that just tells me, you know, a
fixed place on the line and then
says,
okay,
once you move to that fixed
point,
go as far along this direction
vector as you would like.
So I could put 0, 6 there, it
seems like the most natural
choice.
Nothing's stopping me from
putting 3, 12 there either.
Because if I let a be equal to
negative 3, well, that would
slide me back down to 0, 6.
So this is a way I would
describe this line
as involving the span of a
vector.
But it's not the span of the
It's sort of shifted because it
does not contain the origin.
It's a good question.
And actually, just to clarify
that there's several ways you
can do this,
let me also write as an example,
0, 6 plus A times, you know,
3, 12.
And I was going to save this
definition
for a little later, but this set
builder notation for a line, and
we will see this for a plane and
other things shortly,
is called the parametric
form, where the parameter that
we are using here is a.
But sometimes the parameter we
will use is something like T or
S.
We'll see some examples of that
at the moment.
OK,
so what are some of the big
ideas here?
If I have a line in R2 that goes
through the origin,
I know it is the span of a
vector.
This line is not passing through
the origin,
so it is not the span of a
vector.
But we can still express it as
an offset plus the span of a
vector.
And that's why there is this
extra vector up here.
So it's not the span of a
vector,
but it's like a shifted version
of the span of a vector.
What questions do we have so
far?
Awesome.
Is it still in terms of just the
span of one vector even?
Correct, correct.
Because I'm not multiplying that
0, 6 by anything.
Good.
So that's important.
In a little bit, we will
multiply a second vector by
something.
But the shape of that will be
different.
Good.
And I'll say this is the offset.
And if you want to think of the
role of 3-12 here,
you can think of it as telling
us to start there first and then
slide along the line.
One more definition, just
because it'll show up from time
to time.
This line is what's called an
affine line,
and all that is is just a line
that doesn't have to contain 0,
0.
The type of exercise that you
might see in a lab or homework
is using the parametric form of
a line, convert it to y equals
mx plus b form.
And what are some ways you could
do that?
Well,
the direction vector tells you
what the slope is.
It's the y value over the x
value.
And then the position vector at
the start tells you a point on
it.
So you can use tools that you
knew about before to solve for
what that would be.
If you didn't think of that, you
can just plug in two different
values for a.
And that'll give you two points
on the line.
And then you can use tools you
knew about before to find the
equation of a line from two
points.
Now, what about if we move to
R3?
So remember,
we're still thinking of just one
vector,
but in R3.
So now we're imagining this
vector living in
three-dimensional space,
and let's consider the vector v
equals, I don't know, 252.
What is its span?
Yeah.
Is it still just a line in R3?
Yeah,
it's a line in R3.
Those exist.
And it would look something like
this.
And here I might call this the
parametric form
of a line in R3.
Okay, now one of the last things
I said on the previous page was
that this line in R2,
the one in red,
we've described it in parametric
form,
but you could figure out how to
write this line in y equals mx
plus b form.
It's a line in 2d.
What about this line?
A line in 3d and because it's
the span of a vector it passes
through the origin.
Can this be written as a linear
equation?
A couple of things I want to
show you here while you think
about the answer to that.
Can this line be written in the
form y equals mx plus b? Well,
here, there would be a third
direction, so we would have a z.
Can this be written as z equals
ax plus by?
I don't know.
When in doubt,
why don't we go to Desmos?
Maybe it'll tell us.
Okay, So my theory is, OK, let's
see what z equals
something times x plus something
times
y gives us.
2x minus 3y.
Is that a line?
No, what is it?
It's a plane.
So using that understanding, is
it possible to write an equation
in terms of x, y, and z that
describes a line in 3D.
Why?
It is not possible.
Why is it not possible?
I think it's because the v would
be dependent on one specific
variable.
Exactly.
The tricky thing with a line in
3D
is that while it exists in 3D,
it only moves in one direction.
So there's really only one
parameter that you can use to
control your position on it.
Here's another way of thinking
about it.
If there is a function f of xy
that described a
line,
it would mean that I can think
of any x and any y, and it would
tell me a place on the line.
But a line,
imagine I draw a line in this
room, like from my arm to the
exit side over there.
Not every point in the room is
under the line.
Only one very specific
combination of x's and y's lives
in this line.
So it's not the case that if all
of you took the coordinates that
you were at,
like what row, comma, what
column you're at,
that the line passes above you.
It doesn't.
A plane would, though.
If we just took a plane,
remember planes extend
infinitely in all directions,
if I covered the room with the
plane,
you would all be under some
point of it.
Which is why I could express the
plane as a function of x comma
y.
But I can't express a line
because a line only slices
through one little piece of the
3D space.
So there is no linear equation
form of a line in R3.
Instead,
if you want to describe a line
in R3,
you need to use this parametric
form,
OK?
A more complicated way to think
about it, perhaps, is that you
can describe a line using the
intersection of two planes,
which are represented by two
linear equations.
And that's the kind of thing
you'll play around with in
homework four.
But in general, if you want to
describe a line in R3, or R4 or
R something else other than R2,
you need to use this parametric
form.
Now,
the same logic before about
affine lines also applies.
Like, what if I needed to
describe a line in R3 that
doesn't go through the origin?
Well, first you just tack on a
position vector plus A times
whatever direction vector you
want.
That logic still holds.
OK.
So we've looked at a vector in
R3,
a vector in R2, and we know what
they span.
What about one vector in R7?
I'm just going to make it up
here.
And let's just think of
random-looking numbers to put
here.
Pi,
17,
2,
4, 5,
negative 1,
3.72.
OK.
What is the span of v?
It's still just a line, but in
R7.
Good.
Now,
this is a little weird because
we can't visualize this line,
because we can't visualize in
R7.
But we see how this is just a
generalization of our knowledge
of a line in R2 and R3.
Now a term that I will start to
use right now, and we will see
throughout all of next week's
lectures,
is that we will also call this
a one-dimensional
subspace
of R7.
Subspace doesn't need to have
quotes in it.
But when you see subspace,
what I want you to think of is
the word slice.
We're going to be, I'm going to
use this analogy a lot.
Think of a line in R3,
like the example from my arm to
the exit sign, as being a
one-dimensional slice of 3D.
And a plane in this room might
be a two-dimensional slice of
3D.
A line in R7 is like a
one-dimensional slice of R7.
What makes it one-dimensional?
Well there's only like one
variable that is free.
If you pick,
I don't know, what the fourth
component is going to be,
all of the other components are
determined for you based on this
direction vector.
This is an abstract idea.
It's not going to make sense the
first time I say it.
But I want to start planting
those seeds right now.
So are we comfortable,
generally, with the idea of what
a single vector spans, whether
it's an R2, R3,
R17, or R some other thing?
Question? I'm confused on the
line itself.
So when you say four,
the direction that we choose for
span is like of that four?
It means that every point on
that line,
sort of like what this defines
is a,
it tells us the relative sizes
of the components
from each other.
So it doesn't matter what point
on the line we're considering.
The fourth component is always
going to be double this third
component, because we have a 2
and a 4 here,
right?
That's one way to think about
it.
It's related to the fact that if
we go back here, I didn't make
this super clear,
but this line is described by
the direction vector 1, 2.
But that's not the only
direction vector I could have
described it as,
the span of.
I could also call this the span
of the vector 1,000, 2,000
is also the same line,
because that vector points in
the same direction.
And this vector 1,000, 2,000 is
different than the vector 1, 2,
but they both convey the
direction of the line,
and they both tell you their
relative sizes of the components
of the vectors on that line
to each other.
Does that kind of make sense?
Yeah.
Yeah, great question.
OK, questions with lines in Rn,
in general.
Actually, here's one edge case I
should have talked about.
Can you imagine a situation
where one vector in R3 doesn't
span a line?
And if it didn't span a line,
what would it span instead?
Yeah? Is it just a point?
A point.
And how would that happen? It's
like 0, 0, 0.
Yeah, what if you have the zero
vector,
which I will denote with the
number zero with a vector on
top.
The span of the zero vector is
just
the set with the zero vector,
not a line.
The zero vector is like an edge
case that we will have to
consider in most of these
scenarios.
That's one vector in R3.
Sorry, one vector in R2, R3, or
R whatever.
Before we get to two vectors and
more vectors than that,
let's take attendance.
And it's 1,120 on my iPad.
We'll get back at 1,124.
There you go, it should be open.
I mean,
I think we can write it out.
There's seven calendar days,
so I assume this is the end of
day-to-day.
I don't think they understand.
I don't think they
understand.
We haven't even finished the lab
yet.
Nice.
What is the class name for?
I'm gonna be super fast.
She didn't email, like the whole
signal.
I'll put that down.
That's crazy.
I
What?
It's not a lot of money, sorry.
The scene that we faced.
It against me.
But around against the rest.
It actually is a little bit
scary.
If I wasn't working with my
doctor,
it would've been OK.
This one, I think I got it
right, but I want to make sure.
I didn't know this was, like, a
test.
But then I looked,
and it didn't even work out.
It's just been closed or
something.
Of course, I have to check in,
so it's a quiz.
It's just a quiz.
It's a, like,
a quiz.
It's all a theory.
I don't have any time to talk
about it.
OK.
We'll come back together for our
final 25 minutes.
Everyone checked in?
OK, I should close that.
All right, like I said, I always
look at the questions that you
put in on the form.
The one that I really wanted to
address right now is someone
asked,
is this statement true? Is the
span of the vector 1, 2 the same
as the span of the vector 1,000,
2,000?
The answer to that is yes.
Those are the same span.
Any vector you can make as a
linear combination of just 1,
2, you can also make as a linear
combination of 1,000, 2,000.
That's the way you should think
about this.
Right, the spans are the same if
you can make the same outputs
using those building blocks.
Anything you can make with 1, 2,
you can make with 1,000, 2,000.
You just have to multiply 1,000,
2,000 by 1,000th of the amount.
So 5 times 1, 2 is the same as 5
over 1,000 times 1,000, 2,000.
OK, good.
We've discussed in depth the
span of one vector.
And as many of you alluded to,
It's kind of confusing to think
about what a line in R7 looks
like.
Like I said,
it's not something that should
immediately make sense.
It's the kind of thing that you
have to be on the bus thinking
about,
what does that even mean?
And eventually, maybe it'll
click.
Let's think about two vectors
now.
Let's start with two vectors in
R2.
There are three possible
configurations for the span of
two vectors in R2?
What's the edge case we should
think about?
What is the smallest set that
two vectors in R2 could span?
Yeah?
Zero vector?
Yeah, what if they're both the
zero vector?
Then their span is,
well, just the zero vector.
You can't really make anything
with that.
What's the next possibility? I
have two vectors in R2.
Yeah? They both lie along the
same line? Yeah, what if they're
just scalar multiples of each
other?
Then what is their span?
If they both already live on the
same line,
what is their span? Yeah.
This is the configuration I'm
thinking of.
Yeah.
Equal?
It is true that the two vectors
individually have a span that is
equal.
But what I'm now asking is, what
is the span of both of them
together?
That's the question I'm now
thinking about.
It's just the span of one of
them? Yeah.
It's the line that either one of
them span individually.
Good, if they're scalar
multiples of each other,
the span is a line.
That's an important
clarification.
I'm not asking about the spans
of the vectors individually.
I'm asking about what can I make
if I can use both of them at the
same time.
But if my vectors are just 1, 1
and 2, 2,
well, I don't really need the 2,
2 building block, because
anything I can make with 2, 2,
1, 1 can make just as fine,
right?
What is the third case?
I have two vectors in R2.
They're not both the zero
vector.
They're not scalar multiples of
each other.
So now I have two vectors in R2
that point in different
directions.
And what is their span?
What do they span?
Which is all of R2.
Good.
Remember R2, we're thinking
about just the regular xy plane,
like stuff I can draw on my
iPad.
Here's a picture that maybe
helps illuminate the idea.
What I've drawn for us are
linear combinations of a vector
v1 and a vector v2.
And what you're seeing is that
if I multiply the orange vector
and blue vector by various
amounts,
I can reach any point in 2D just
by taking a little bit of v1 and
a little bit of v2.
I can think of any target.
And there is always a way to
figure out how much of v1 and
how much of v2 to take to reach
that target.
Okay, like for example,
I could,
to, you know, to get here,
I could go here and then
opposite the blue vector,
something like that.
That's a legal way to
end up at that x.
Which means the vector whose end
point is at that x can be made
using the orange vector and the
blue vector.
Okay?
If I have two vectors in R2 that
point in different directions,
they span all of R2.
All that means is that any third
vector in R2 you want,
you can make it using the first
two.
And one sort of way to think
about this is that R2,
which is just our regular x-y
plane that we're familiar with,
only has two independent
directions,
like it has an x-axis and it has
a y-axis.
So if I have two building
blocks, each of which
contributes some new
information,
I should be able to make
everything in R2.
OK?
And I never explicitly mentioned
this before,
but in some of the examples
you've worked on in lab and
homeworks recently, we've
implicitly taken advantage of
this fact.
If I just gave you two vectors
in R2 that didn't point in the
same direction and gave you a
third vector and said make the
third vector using a linear
combination of the first two,
you're always able to do it.
Okay? And the only case in which
you wouldn't be able to do it is
if the two vectors I gave you
were scalar multiples of each
other.
This is the kind of thing you
need to convince yourself of.
Just make up two vectors in R2,
then make up a third one, and
just try and make the third one
using a linear combination of
the first two.
And as long as the first two
aren't scalar multiples of each
other, you will be able to do
it.
So that's two vectors in R2.
What about two vectors in R3?
What are the possibilities?
Same three possibilities to
consider.
Their span could be the zero
vector,
their span could be a line, or
their span could be what is the
third thing?
Yeah.
A plane.
I don't know why this guy is
just rotating freely.
Good.
There's a bit more intuition for
some of these things in the
notes.
Like,
what would happen if you had two
vectors in R2
that are scalar multiples of
each other? What would happen
from the equation perspective if
you tried to find a third vector
as a linear combination of the
first two? Here's a good example
of where you wouldn't be able to
do that.
Here this is asking,
can I use the orange vector 1 1
and the blue vector 2 2 to make
8 11?
You can't do it because any
linear combination of 1 1 2 2 is
gonna have both of its
components equal and 8 11
doesn't have both of its
components equal.
So you didn't like if you try
and solve there will be no
solution for a 1 and a 2.
It's the kind of thing that you
will review in homework 4.
But anyways, now we're looking
at two vectors in R3.
my orange vector and my blue
vector,
and what you're seeing in gray
are a few of their linear
combinations.
What you should notice is that
they all live on this same flat
plane.
You can imagine drawing a sheet
of paper in 3D in which all of
these vectors live,
and all of the linear
combinations of v1 and v2 here.
I should zoom in a little more
here to make this clear, But all
of these linear combinations of
v1 and v2 live on this plane,
okay?
So if a third vector that I
present you with is on that
plane Well, then you can make it
with v1 and v2.
If it's not, like if I give you
a third vector
That's poking somewhere out of
this plane.
Well, then you can't make it
with v1 and v2
Okay, and that plane is
visualized here
Okay
Let me
Take a screenshot of this and
put this in the iPad notes.
What questions do we have about
the fact
that two vectors in R3 span a
plane as long as those
vectors don't point in the same
direction?
Are we comfortable with that
idea?
Now, how can you describe that
plane?
there are two ways you can do
it.
You can describe it in
parametric form,
which would be something like
the set A
times V1,
whatever V1 is, plus B times V2,
where A and B are real numbers.
Or you could describe that plane
as a linear equation.
On Desmos, 10 minutes ago, we
discovered that equations of the
form z equals ax plus by
describe planes in R3.
So there is a way to find a
linear equation for a plane in
R3 given the two vectors, given
two vectors that span it.
Another form instead of z equals
ax plus by is ax plus By
plus Cz equals 0.
And when you see chapter 4.4,
which talks more about how you
write it in this form,
you will see why we prefer this
form.
And the short answer is that if
you look at this equation, Ax
plus By plus Cz equals 0,
if you consider all of the x,
y's and z's that satisfy this,
they're really just describing
the set of vectors that are
orthogonal to the vector ABC.
Note that this just looks like
the dot product of XYZ with ABC,
and it's saying this plane is
all of the vectors that are
orthogonal to ABC.
And the way we'll think about
it, and this was actually the
last question in yesterday's
lab, which I'm pretty sure you
didn't get to,
but this was the idea,
if you consider a vector n that
is orthogonal to the plane, if
you find that,
then the components of n are the
coefficients of x, y, and z in
this equation.
And again, you will practice
with this in the upcoming weeks.
I'm not expecting you to
automatically know how to do
that.
So that's the situation with two
vectors in R3.
What about two vectors in a
space that we can't visualize,
R7?
Well they could span the zero
vector, they could span a line
in R7, or they could span a
plane in R7.
But what was the new word that I
introduced to describe slices of
space?
Using that new word, what would
I describe the span of these two
vectors?
Yeah,
Sam.
Subspace?
Yeah, I would call it a
two-dimensional subspace of R7.
So another question that someone
asked in the Google form was,
is a subspace, is that word
unique to lines?
No.
It's unique to all slices, which
you should think of as flat
objects in high dimensions.
Just like a line is flat, it
doesn't have any curves.
A plane is flat, it doesn't have
any curves.
Whatever the span of these two
vectors is,
while we can't visualize it,
hopefully it's not too hard to
believe that it doesn't have any
bends or curves.
Whatever it is, it's flat
wherever it lives.
And that comes from just the way
that we add vectors, tip to tip.
So the span of these two
vectors, v1 and v2,
which, again,
I would write in parametric
form, maybe like this,
a1 times this thing
plus
a2.
It doesn't really matter again
if you use A1 and A2 or AB here,
we only have two, so I could
have used A and B.
It's this set
where I loop over all possible
values of A1 and A2,
and what I would say is that
this is a two-dimensional
subspace of R7.
And remember, a subspace,
I want you to think of
intuitively as a slice.
I'll give you a formal
definition on Tuesday.
OK.
So we have some understanding
that if I have two vectors,
whether they're an R2, R3, or
R7, or wherever,
their span could be just the
zero vector.
It could be just a line if they
point in the same direction.
Or it could be a two-dimensional
subspace of whatever universe
they live in.
A two-dimensional subspace of R2
is like a two-dimensional slice
of a thing that only has two
dimensions.
So it's a whole thing.
It's all of R2.
A two-dimensional slice of R3,
that's a plane,
which we saw several examples
of.
A two-dimensional slice of R7,
hard to think about what that
means, but take this as a
definition for now.
It's like a slice of
seven-dimensional space in which
I can only move in two
directions.
The directions in which I can
move are defined by these two
spanning vectors,
and the amounts by which I can
move are a1 and a2 here.
Okay, one thing I want to
emphasize before we move to the
three vector case and more
general,
here I've written this plane in
parametric form as a times v1
plus b times v2.
Are those the only two vectors
that define this plane, or could
I have defined this plane in
parametric form using other
vectors?
Could I do it with other
vectors, or is there something
special about this v1 and v2?
Yeah.
You could do scalar multiples,
right?
I could do scalar multiples, or
I could do just other vectors on
the plane.
Any two vectors that live on
this plane, they don't need to
be scalar multiples of v1 and v2
specifically.
I can pick any two vectors that
live in this plane as long as
they don't point in the same
direction they span this plane
Okay, so I could have picked
You know call that v3 and
Call that v4 that's a terrible
color to use here
OK,
the span of v1 and v2 is also
equal to the span of v3 and v4.
Let's move this over here.
Do we see why that's the case?
I picked two vectors that are
not pointing in the same
direction that live in the
plane.
Yeah, Emma.
Just to clarify, when you say
that two vectors pointing in the
same direction,
do you mean that they're equal?
Well, first to clarify here, I
meant I picked two vectors that
don't point in the same
direction.
But when I say point in the same
direction, I mean are scalar
multiples of each other,
like 1, 1 and 2, 2, for example.
Not equal, but they have the
same span.
Good.
Good clarification.
I don't think these colors all
need to be accurate, but
whatever, it's OK.
Forces me to go slower.
OK, are we clear on why the span
of v1 and v2 here is the same as
the span of v3 and v4?
OK.
And these are all just random
choices on this plane.
We could all think of two
different vectors that live on
the plane.
And this plane is the span of
those two vectors.
OK,
so we've looked at the span of
one vector.
We've looked at the span of two
vectors.
Let's think about three vectors
We'll start with R2 then think
about R3 then think about in
general and I'm hoping we can
get to the like main takeaway in
general by the end of today
Okay, what about three vectors
in R2?
What could they span
They could span the zero vector
sure they could span a line if I
just give you three vectors that
already live on the same line
They could span all of R2
Because we know that you only
need two vectors to span all of
r2, right? If I give you just
two building blocks in r2
That don't point in the same
direction.
I know they already span all of
r2
So what does having a third
building block enable in r2?
Yeah
Nothing,
the third one is kind of just
there to stir stuff up.
Okay, it doesn't allow you to
make anything that two vectors
couldn't already,
okay?
The span of three vectors in R2,
the most it could be is still
just all of R2, okay?
If I'm drawing vectors on my
page,
doesn't matter how many there
are, they can't somehow
magically jump out of my iPad,
right? They're stuck to live in
R2,
okay?
So here I've drawn
two configurations of three
vectors in R2 that are subtly
different.
On the right, I have three
vectors in R2, and none of them
point in the same direction.
But still,
one of them is redundant.
I could delete this pink vector
because it can be made using the
blue and orange.
Because using the logic from
before,
the blue and orange can make
everything in R2.
And this vector in pink is in R2
already.
So the span of these three
vectors is the span of just the
blue and orange.
The pink one doesn't really
change the span.
There's nothing special about
the pink one.
I just picked on it arbitrarily,
I could use the same argument
with the pink and blue.
I can make the orange with the
pink and blue, so the span of
the pink and blue is the same as
the span of all three of them.
The configuration is subtly
different on the left, because
the span of the blue and orange
is just a line, while the span
of the orange and pink is all of
R2.
So it's still the case that you
don't need all three of these,
but if you deleted the pink one,
then the span would actually
change, whereas on the right, if
you deleted the pink one, the
span wouldn't change.
Do we see the subtle difference
between these configurations?
Either way,
what we're dealing with is the
consequence of having three
vectors in R2.
No matter what,
the most that any number of
vectors in R2 can span is all of
R2.
But the fact that we have some
extra redundant vectors
actually will make things more
complicated, as we will see on
Tuesday.
The fact that we have a third
vector here now means that if we
try and go make a fourth vector
using a linear combination of
these three building blocks,
there will actually be
infinitely many ways we can do
it,
which is annoying for reasons we
will see and connect back to
linear regression in just a bit.
Actually,
we can make that connection now.
Someone asked on the forum, what
is the purpose of all of this?
Like I said,
the purpose of all of this is
that it's all going to tie back
to the linear regression problem
of finding optimal model
parameters.
Okay, imagine a world in which
we find optimal model
parameters, optimal W stars,
that tell us how much to
multiply each input variable by.
But imagine there wasn't just
one optimal set of W's.
Imagine there are infinitely
many,
some of which sometimes
multiplied, pretend we were
predicting commute times using
departure time and some other
stuff.
What if some of those infinitely
many solutions multiplied
departure time by a positive
number and some multiplied
departure time by a negative
number.
Then it's hard to understand
what the effect of predicted
commute time is by departure
time if sometimes it's
multiplied by a positive number
and sometimes it's multiplied by
a negative number, which is one
of the things that can happen
when there are infinitely many
ways to make one output given
some inputs, which is why it's
annoying to have redundant
vectors in our collection of
building blocks.
This is the kind of thing we
will discuss more over the next
week.
And I'm just giving you a
preview of that now.
So this is three vectors in R2.
What about three vectors in R3?
There are four possibilities for
what three vectors in R3 could
span.
The first one and second one are
perhaps the easiest to think
about.
What if I gave you three vectors
that are all the zero vector?
Well, their span is just the 0
vector.
OK,
that's out of the way.
What if I give you three vectors
in R3, but they all live on the
same line?
I give you the vectors 1, 1, 1,
2, 2, 2, and 3, 3, 3.
Well, then I'm still stuck to
the same line that just 1, 1, 1
spans.
How would three vectors in R3
span only a plane?
Yeah, Sam?
Two are the same?
That's one possibility, but they
don't not need to all will be
none of them need to be the same
for the span to still just be a
plane.
Not the same scalar multiples, I
mean.
There's a way that this could
happen, and none of them are
scalar multiples of each other,
Yeah, Tiago.
Everyone's a linear combination.
Yeah, what if the third vector
can be made using a linear
combination of the first two?
What if we go back to this
example here?
Before we said the span of v1
and v2 Is the same as the span
of v3 and v4.
That's true
Those both are also equal to the
span of v1 v2 and v3
because v3 Can be made with v1
and v2
So v3 is not a new building
block if I already have v1 and
v2
What I'm saying is if you look
at v1 and v2 in isolation that
makes the plane I look at v3 and
v4 in isolation.
They also make the plane
But if v1 and v2 already make
the whole plane And having v3 as
well doesn't really change
anything.
Their span is still just a
plane.
Even though v1, v2, and v3, none
of them are scalar multiples of
each other.
v3 is a linear combination of v1
and v2, though,
because they all live on the
plane.
So to clarify,
the span could be a plane if the
three.
Okay.
What's the final possibility?
I have three vectors in R3.
Their span could be the zero
vector, it could be a line, it
could be a plane.
What else could it be?
If it's none of those
possibilities, what is left as a
possibility?
Yeah.
Like all points in R3? Yeah,
just all of R3.
How would that happen?
Well,
pretend I start with two vectors
in R3 that don't point in the
same direction.
We know they spin a plane.
Pretend it's these two.
But what if I just think of a
third vector that's not on the
plane?
Then,
what that in effect allows me to
do is make any vector that's on
the plane and then scale it up
or down by that third vector.
So it allows me to take my plane
and all the vectors that live on
it and then also make any vector
that I could get by sort of
translating this plane.
What that, in effect, allows me
to do is reach anything in R3.
And that happens when you have
three vectors
in which none of them are linear
combinations of each other.
Now just to quickly recap that
subspace terminology
This set with just a zero
vector.
I would call a zero dimensional
subspace
Of r3, what do you think I would
call a plane?
Yeah
Sorry, can you please repeat
that? It's a subspace.
Not quite.
It's a subspace no matter what.
The question is, what is the
dimension of the subspace?
Two,
good.
It's a two-dimensional subspace
of R3.
So what we're seeing is that if
you have some vectors in Rn, and
they span some dimensional
subspace of Rn.
And what we've seen are just the
cases where you have one vector,
two vector, or three vectors.
What we're going to do when we
come back is give you the
general definition.
OK, I have d vectors in Rn.
What do they span?
That's where we will pick up
with on Tuesday.
Yeah, I've had the Indian places
right here, not many years off
from when I had the brick.
So we checked in then.
Oh,
look at this.
Cool.
Yeah.
So I finished it.
I definitely failed the lab.
I did them on like Monday.
Have you done it?
It's really not that bad.
It's like very similar to this
lab.
This is very similar to this
It's just like I think it's like
11 to 20.
I think they do,
and they get paid to do it.
You're good, you're good, you're
good,
you're fine.
This is cool.
But, but,
what's the frequency of how long
this place is going to take?
I really like it,
yeah.
Because R2 is the set of vectors
with two real numbers in it,
but every vector on that plane
is described with three
components.
So a plane in R3 is not the same
as R2,
though they're both
two-dimensional.
R2 is the set of all vectors in
which there's an x component and
a y component.
The plane in R3, every vector on
it has an x, y, and z component.
There's a pattern to them, and
they all live on the same plane.
Yeah, another question.
Do you have an office already?
Yeah.
Do you have an office?
Yeah, I come from it.
It's in my office.
Yo,
what up?
I'm just teaming up.
8x?
No,
I think so.
Wait, no.
Yeah, I'm almost there.
Thank you.